# **Adrien Bolland**

PhD Student



(+32) 4 79 96 96 77



https://adrienbolland.github.io/



adrien.bolland@uliege.be

# About me —

I am a PhD student in artificial intelligence at the university of Liège doing researches in deep reinforcement learning with applications to the renewable energy transition. More specifically, my work focuses on applications of deep reinforcement learning for energy trading as well as on the adaptation of these algorithms to solve joint design and control problems. I am open to discuss or collaborate on research projects.

## Education

Since 2020 PhD student in reinforcement learning

University of Liège

Advisor: Damien Ernst (dernst@uliege.be).

2018 - 2020 Master student in electrical engineering in signal processing and intelligent roboticsUniversity of Liège

Summa Cum Laude - 91 %.

Bachelor student in electrical engineering and computer science

University of Liège

Magna Cum Laude - 78 %.

## Experience

2015-2018

2019 Internship in the Market Modeling & Market View department at Engle Belgium

**Engie Brussels** 

Internship focusing on the forecasting of the electricity imbalance prices.

2019 Junior researcher at the Montefiore institute

University of Liège

Internship focusing on the study of deep RL solutions for trading on the intraday electricity market.

2019 Summer school on bandits and RL.

University of Lille

Summer school organized by Seguel and Inria.

2017 - 2019 Pupil-monitor.

University of Liège

Monitor in applied geometry, C-language,

electromagnetic energy conversion, and computer structures.

#### Publications

Jointly Learning Environments and Control Policies with Projected Stochastic Gradient Ascent

Adrien Bolland, Ioannis Boukas, Mathias Berger, Damien Ernst

arXiv preprint arXiv :2006.01738

Distributional Reinforcement Learning with Unconstrained Monotonic Neural Networks

Thibaut Théate, Antoine Wehenkel, Adrien Bolland, Gilles Louppe, Damien Ernst

arXiv preprint arXiv :2106.03228, 2021

Graph-Based Optimization Modeling Language: A Tutorial

Mathias Berger, Adrien Bolland, Bardhyl Miftari, Hatim Djelassi, Damien Ernst

preprint, 2021

A deep reinforcement learning framework for continuous intraday market bidding

Ioannis Boukas, Damien Ernst, Thibaut Théate, Adrien Bolland, Alexandre Huynen, Martin Buchwald,

Christelle Wynants, Bertrand Cornélusse

Machine Learning, 2021

## Teaching

**Numerical Optimization** 

University of Liège

Introductory course on conic programming and convex optimization algorithms.

Reinforcement Learning

University of Liège

Course introducing dynamic programming, bandit theory, and reinforcement learning.

Energy Markets

University of Liège

Introductory course on the organization of the energy markets in Europe.



 ${\it Mathematics} \ \ {\it Algebra}, \ {\it Analysis}, \ {\it Numerical analysis} \ \ {\it and optimization}, \ \ {\it and System theory}.$ 

 ${\bf Applied\ Mathematics\ Deep\ Learning,\ Reinforcement\ Learning,\ Optimization,\ and\ Statistics.}$ 

Computer Science Programming techniques, Data structures and Computer structures.

Physics Global formation as an engineer with specialization in electromagnetism and electricity.

# Languages

French Native proficiency.

Dutch Bilingual proficiency.

English Professional working proficiency.

#### [Interests]

I like music and played piano during three years. I have played tennis and I do ice-skating in my free time.